iab.net 2009-06-05

# IAB - Privacy Policy

_This Privacy Policy was last modified and is effective as of Wednesday, August 20, 2008_

**IAB Privacy Policy** (including your California Privacy Rights)

This is our official Privacy Policy which forms part of your legal agreement with us UNDER OUR [TERMS OF USE](http://www.iab.net/legal_disclaimer). Please read our Privacy Policy carefully to be sure you understand how we collect and use information and under what circumstances we share information about you.

Any terms not defined in this Privacy Policy are defined in our [Terms of Use](http://www.iab.net/legal_disclaimer).

WE CAN MODIFY THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to modify, add or delete provisions of this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time, and we will post a notice and the effective date of any change on our Website. If you have given us your email address to use or we have some other means of contacting you, we may also do so in any or all of those ways, but our posting is the only official and required notice you will receive. Your use of our Website after the effective date of any such modification, means you accept and agree to be bound by the Privacy Policy, as modified. We urge you to come back to this web page and review this Privacy Policy regularly so that you remain aware of the terms and conditions that apply to you.

COLLECTING PERSONAL INFORMATION

"Personal Information" means any information obtained through your use of our Website which might reasonably be used to specifically identify you and may include your name, title, company, address, email and phone number, among other things. If and when we collect Personal Information from you, we do so on a voluntary basis and this enables us to give you access to the IABConnect, members-only portion of our Website which may include features, functions, promotions, products and services not generally available to non-members.

We do not sell or rent your Personal Information to others. If necessary, our Website may collect payment and payment instrument information from you for the purpose of billing you for products and services you purchase through our Website. Bear in mind, as noted in the section below entitled Advertisers, Sponsors and Links to Others, if you leave our Website whether by clicking or selecting an advertisement, re-directing your browser or otherwise, their terms and conditions, privacy and other policies and practices will apply, not ours. If you elect to use our ‘Refer-A-Member’ service in order to tell someone else about us, we will ask you to provide your email address and the email address of the individual you wish to inform. We will use this information to send a one-time automated email inviting them to visit our Website and indicating the invitation arose from your suggestion. We do not retain the information obtained in this manner for longer than necessary to transmit and confirm the email and we do not use it for any other purpose.

COLLECTING NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION

When you use our Website, we often use third party operational service providers (see Disclosure To Third Parties  below) and technology that can recognize, collect and transmit information that is associated with you or your computer and browser, but which does not personally identify you. Although the term "cookie" commonly is used to refer to a small text file stored on a computer that keeps track of your visits to web sites and/or can contain log-in information so you don’t have to re-enter information each time you visit, we will use the term "cookie" to refer generically to any technology that can recognize, collect or transmit information about your visits to our Websites. "Cookie" information typically includes such data as the Internet or web domain that referred you, the type of operating system and browser you are using, the date and time of your visit, information relating to activities on our Websites (e.g., ‘clickstream’ data) and other technical attributes of your visits to our Website. No personally identifiable information is collected by this process and we use the information collected through cookies to analyze trends, administer our Websites, track movements on our Website and gather aggregate demographic information about visitors so we can continually improve our Website.

Cookies store information that allows our Website to recognize a users’ computer or access device each time it is used to visit our Website and cookies can keep count of how often you return to our Website. Cookies can also track how you use our Website, your preferences for features and functions and can store information such as your log-in information, so you don’t have to re-enter them each time you return to our Website. We do not use cookies to retrieve information from your computer for purposes that are unrelated to our Website or your interaction with our Website.

You may stop or restrict cookies on your computer or purge them from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences and you should consult the operating instructions that apply to your browser for instructions should you wish to do so and in general to determine how best to configure your browser settings to meet your requirements. Note that if you ‘turn off,’ purge or disable cookies, although you may still use our Website, you may not be able to use all of the features, functions or services available on our Website.

HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

We will only use information we collect or obtain when you use our Website as described in this Privacy Policy, for our internal research purposes or to ensure compliance with our [Terms of Use](http://www.iab.net/legal_disclaimer). If, at any time in the future, we decide we are going to use your Personal Information in a way that differs from our then current Privacy Policy, we will give you notice as described in the section above entitled We Can Modify This Privacy Policy, at least 30 days’ in advance notice. We will provide you the opportunity to decline consent ("opt-out") of such differing uses.

ADVERTISERS, CO-SPONSORS AND LINKS TO OTHERS

Our Website may contain or display information from sponsors, co-sponsors, advertisers, operational service providers or others that offer to make information, products and services available, provide opportunities to participate in promotions or engage in activities or that link or redirect your browser to other websites, web pages, materials or organizations. We may also use third parties for the purpose of administering, operating, configuring our Website, maintaining and providing internal support for our Website and Content on our Website, to display and serve advertising on our Website, for distributing our online, email, messaged or web-based newsletters and other information. We will refer to these third parties as our "operational service providers." Even if we have a relationship with a third party you may encounter or see on our Website, the advertising, links or references to third parties or any of their websites, including any cookies or other technology they may use, are not under our control and they have their own terms, conditions, policies and practices that apply to you in connection with their websites, including those concerning collection, use and disclosure of your information (including Personal Information).

Some IAB Services, such as seminars, educational events, conferences, newsletters and discussion groups, may be co-sponsored in conjunction with other companies that not under the control of the IAB. Whenever we are involved in the provision of these Services, we will disclose the name of our co-sponsor and to the extent they are Website-based, we will advise you if any of the privacy practices, policies or terms that apply to those particular Services are different from those set forth in this Privacy Policy. Co-sponsors of these IAB Services are not under our control and when you participate, register or engage in other online activities related to these co-sponsored IAB Services, you should be aware that you are providing your information, which may include Personal Information, to us and the co-sponsor and that their policies, practices, terms and conditions, and not ours, apply to their collection and use of your information.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Website or take advantage of advertised offers, links or other references, many of which may direct you or your Internet browser to websites or web pages of another party. You should read their privacy statements and the terms and conditions that apply, because we are not responsible for any of the terms or conditions, privacy practices, the content, functions, features, activities or transactions you may engage in when you are not using our Website.

DISCLOSURE TO THIRD PARTIES

We always have the right to disclose your Personal Information to our operational service providers that we engage to assist us in connection with our Website, IABConnect or other services we provide. We always request that our operational service providers protect your privacy and not disclose your Personal Information to third party marketers that are not associated with our Website, nor are they permitted to use your Personal Information for their own marketing or promotional purposes.

If we use an operational service provider to serve advertising when you visit our Website, they, in connection with our Website, may use information about your visit to our Website in order to serve advertisements about products and services that may be of interest to you. In the course of serving advertisements to our Website, our operational service provider may use cookies. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by the operational service provider we use for this service, please click here: [www.doubleclick.net/us/corporate/privacy](http://www.doubleclick.net/us/corporate/privacy)

We also currently use an operational service provider to measure our Website traffic and they may also information (but not Personal Information) about your use of our Website to help us improve our Website. If you would like more information about how the operational service provider we use for this service collects and uses this information, please visit: [www.liveanalysis.com/Privacy#REF9](http://www.liveanalysis.com/Privacy%23REF9).

We also reserve the right to make your Personal Information available:

· When compelled by a governmental agency, law, regulation, a court or other legal process;

· If we believe you are, have or may violate any law, regulation or our [Terms of Use](http://www.iab.net/legal_disclaimer);

· If we believe you are or may be a threat to safety, security, property, interests or rights of us or anyone else;

· In order to investigate, respond to or resolve problems or inquiries or protect, enforce or defend our rights, assets and/or interests;

· In a merger, acquisition, change of control, joint venture or other business combination.

OPTING OUT

If you register on or with our Website, you are agreeing and consenting to receive information and updates about your use of our Website or our Services (e.g., IABConnect) for which you register. You may opt out of receiving any or all of these communications by sending an email to unsubscribe@iab.net, by following the unsubscribe procedures on our Website or by following the unsubscribe instructions we will include in each email we send you. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your request to opt out or you continue to receive these communications after a reasonable time for us to remove you from our mailing list, you should contact TRUSTe through the TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process (http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with our Website to resolve the concerns you may have in this regard.

SECURITY 

As you may appreciate, the Internet is a public network of networks and we cannot guarantee that communications between you and the IAB or others to, through or from our Website, will be free from unauthorized access or interference by third parties such as hackers. By using our Website, you are agreeing to assume this risk and any and all responsibility and liability that may arise. That said, the security of your Personal Information is important to us and when possible we attempt to provide secure transmissions by using encryption software. We have also put in place reasonable physical, electronic and operational procedures to safeguard information and we limit access to your Personal Information to only those employees who need access in order to perform their duties.

YOUR RIGHTS REGARDING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We will provide you with a mechanism to allow and enable you to correct or update the Personal Information in our current records that we have obtained from you. You can always review and change your Personal Information by contacting us by email at  privacy@iab.net or by telephone at 212.380.4728. Certain Personal Information may not be changed without authentication (e.g., birth date) and you may be asked to provide additional information to allow us to confirm your identity in order to change those. If you ask us to remove your Personal Information, we still reserve the right to retain as much of your Personal Information and for so long as necessary to comply with our legal, regulatory, internal audit and record-keeping requirements.

TRUSTe PRIVACY PROGRAM

The IAB is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy policy covers the Website www.iab.net and http://iabconnect.intronetworks.com (which we refer to herein as our "Website"). To demonstrate our commitment to our user’s privacy, we have agreed to disclose our Website information practices and have our privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Patrick Dolan, at [patrick@iab.net](mailto:patrick@iab.net). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe through the TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process (http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php). TRUSTE will serve as a liaison with our Website to resolve your concerns. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through our Website, and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from our Website or other websites.

YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

If you are a resident of the State of California, under the California Civil Code, you have the right to request information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options from companies conducting business in California. To do so, send us a request for information indicating your preference as to how you would like us to respond to your request (i.e., email or postal mail). To request such information, either send an email to our designated Privacy Administrator at privacy@iab.net or you may contact us via postal mail, proper postage prepaid, at:

Privacy Administrator  
Interactive Advertising Bureau  
116 E. 27th Street  
New York, New York 10016  
Attn: Your California Privacy Rights

**All requests sent via postal mail must be labeled "Your California Privacy Rights" on the envelope or post card and clearly stated on the actual request.** For all requests, please include your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. (Your street address is optional if you wish to receive a response to your request via email. Please include your zip code for our own recordkeeping.) **We will not accept requests via the telephone or by facsimile.** We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information.

CONTACT US

For questions or concerns relating to privacy, we can be contacted at: privacy@iab.net or 212.380.4728 or by mail, proper postage prepaid, at Interactive Advertising Bureau, Inc., 116 E. 27th Street, New York, New York, 10016, Attention: Privacy Administrator.

TRUSTe can be contacted at [www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php).
